<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Envi</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <!--Astilbe-->
    <string name="Astilbe">
        \t<b>Plant Name: </b> Astilbe\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Astilbe\n\t<b>Description:</b> Astilbes are perennial plants renowned for their beautiful feathery plumes of flowers in shades of pink, red, purple, and white, accompanied by fern-like foliage. They thrive in habitats that provide partial shade and moist, well-drained soil rich in organic matter. To care for astilbes, it is crucial to ensure regular watering, especially during dry periods, and the application of mulch to retain moisture and suppress weeds. Pruning should be performed in late fall or early spring to remove faded flower stalks and dead foliage, while dividing the clumps every few years helps maintain their vigor. Additionally, annual fertilization with a balanced slow-release or liquid fertilizer promotes robust growth. Vigilance against common pests and diseases, such as powdery mildew, is essential, and appropriate treatments should be applied as needed to ensure the health and vitality of astilbes.
    </string>

    <!--Bellflower-->
    <string name="Bellflower">
        \t<b>Plant Name: </b> Bellflower\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Campanula\n\t<b>Description:</b> Campanulas, also known as bellflowers, are a diverse group of flowering plants characterized by their bell-shaped or star-shaped blossoms. They come in various sizes and colors, including shades of blue, purple, pink, and white. Campanulas can be found in a wide range of habitats, from alpine meadows to woodland edges and even rock gardens. To care for campanulas, it is important to provide them with well-drained soil that is rich in organic matter. They generally prefer full sun to partial shade, depending on the species. Regular watering is necessary to keep the soil evenly moist, especially during dry spells. Deadheading spent flowers promotes continuous blooming, and cutting back the plants after flowering can encourage a second flush of blooms. It\'s also beneficial to divide overcrowded clumps every few years to maintain their vigor. Monitoring for pests, such as slugs and snails, and treating them accordingly ensures the health and appearance of campanulas.
    </string>

    <!--Black-eyed Susan-->
    <string name="BlackEyedSusan">
        \t<b>Plant Name: </b> Black-eyed Susan\n\t<b>Scientific Name: </b> Rudbeckia hirta\n\t<b>Description:</b> Black-eyed susan is a relatively large wildflower, ranging from 30-90 cm. in height. As indicated by its name, the flower head has a prominent black or dark-brown central cone that is surrounded by rich, yellow, petal-like rays. The leaves are long, lanceolate, and rough to the touch. The stalk is robust and also coarsely textured.
    </string>

    <!--Marigold-->
    <string name="Marigold">
        \t<b>Plant Name:</b> Marigold\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Calendula\n\t<b>Description:</b> Calendulas, also known as pot marigolds, are cheerful annual flowering plants native to the Mediterranean region. They are characterized by their vibrant and daisy-like flowers in shades of yellow and orange, with some varieties featuring bicolor or pastel hues. Calendulas can thrive in a variety of habitats, but they prefer full sun exposure and well-drained soil. They are commonly found in gardens, borders, and containers. Caring for calendulas involves providing them with ample sunlight and regular watering, allowing the soil to dry slightly between waterings. Deadheading spent flowers promotes prolonged blooming, and removing any damaged or diseased foliage helps maintain the plant\'s health. Calendulas are generally resistant to pests and diseases, but keeping an eye out for common issues like aphids or powdery mildew is recommended. With their easy-going nature and bright blooms, calendulas add a burst of color to any garden.
    </string>

    <!--California Poppy-->
    <string name="CaliforniaPoppy">
        \t<b>Plant Name:</b> California Poppy\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Eschscholzia\n\t<b>Description:</b> Eschscholzia, commonly known as California poppies, are beautiful flowering plants native to California and parts of North America. They are known for their striking orange, yellow, or white flowers that resemble delicate cups. Eschscholzia thrive in habitats with full sun and well-drained soil, making them ideal for rock gardens, meadows, or dry slopes. To care for Eschscholzia, provide them with a sunny location and avoid overwatering as they are drought-tolerant. It is best to let the soil dry out between watering. Deadheading spent flowers encourages continuous blooming and prevents self-seeding. These hardy plants generally do not require fertilization but benefit from occasional organic mulch to conserve moisture and suppress weeds. Eschscholzia are generally pest and disease resistant, making them a low-maintenance choice for adding vibrant color to your garden.
    </string>

    <!--Carnation-->
    <string name="Carnation">
        \t<b>Plant Name: </b> Carnation\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Dianthus\n\t<b>Description:</b> Dianthus, commonly known as carnations or pinks, are charming flowering plants that come in a variety of colors, including shades of pink, red, white, and purple. They are native to Europe and Asia and are known for their delicate petals and lovely fragrance. Dianthus thrive in habitats with full sun exposure and well-drained soil. They are often found in gardens, borders, rock gardens, or containers. To care for dianthus, provide them with a sunny location and soil that is fertile and well-drained. Regular watering is important, particularly during dry periods, but be cautious not to over-water as they can be susceptible to root rot. Deadheading spent flowers encourages prolonged blooming, and removing any yellow or damaged foliage helps maintain the plant\'s overall health. Fertilize dianthus with a balanced fertilizer during the growing season to promote healthy growth and abundant blooms. These versatile plants are relatively low-maintenance but may benefit from some protection against common pests such as aphids or slugs. With their vibrant colors and sweet fragrance, dianthus add beauty and charm to any garden setting.
    </string>

    <!--Daisy-->
    <string name = "Daisy">
      \t<b>Plant Name:</b> Daisy\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Bellis\n\t<b>Description:</b> Bellis, commonly known as daisies or English daisies, are delightful flowering plants that are native to Europe and Asia. They are characterized by their small, colorful flowers with a central disk surrounded by delicate petals in shades of white, pink, or red. Bellis typically thrive in cool, temperate habitats and are often found in lawns, meadows, or cottage gardens. To care for Bellis, provide them with a location that receives partial to full sun and well-drained soil. Regular watering is important to keep the soil evenly moist, especially during dry spells. Deadheading spent flowers promotes continuous blooming, and trimming back the plants after flowering can help maintain their shape and prevent self-seeding. These low-growing plants are generally not prone to serious pest or disease issues, making them relatively low-maintenance. With their charming and timeless beauty, Bellis bring a touch of nostalgia and grace to any garden.
    </string>

    <!--Tickseed-->
    <string name="Tickseed">
        \t<b>Plant Name: </b> Tickseed\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Coreopsis\n\t<b>Description:</b> Coreopsis, commonly known as tickseed, are lovely perennial flowering plants that are native to North America. They are known for their daisy-like flowers that come in vibrant shades of yellow, gold, and pink. Coreopsis can thrive in a variety of habitats, including meadows, prairies, and garden borders. To care for Coreopsis, provide them with a sunny location and well-drained soil. These plants are relatively drought-tolerant and do not require excessive watering, but regular watering during dry spells will promote healthy growth and blooming. Deadheading spent flowers encourages continuous flowering, and cutting back the plants after blooming can stimulate fresh growth. Coreopsis are generally low-maintenance and do not require fertilization, but a layer of organic mulch can help conserve moisture and suppress weed growth. These plants are typically resistant to pests and diseases. With their bright and cheerful blooms, Coreopsis adds a splash of color and beauty to any garden.
    </string>

    <!--Daffodil-->
    <string name="Daffodil">
        \t<b>Plant Name: </b> Daffodil\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Narcissus\n\t<b>Description:</b> Narcissus, commonly known as daffodils, are captivating spring-blooming bulbous plants native to Europe, North Africa, and parts of Asia. They are characterized by their vibrant trumpet-shaped flowers in shades of yellow, white, and orange, often accompanied by distinct, strap-like leaves. Narcissus thrive in habitats that receive full to partial sun and have well-drained soil. They can be found in gardens, meadows, and naturalized landscapes. To care for narcissus, plant the bulbs in the fall, ensuring they are placed at a depth of about 2-3 times their own height. Regular watering is necessary during the growing season, but avoid overwatering to prevent bulb rot. Once the flowers fade, allow the foliage to naturally wither and turn yellow, as this process helps the bulbs store energy for the following year\'s bloom. Narcissus bulbs are generally low-maintenance and do not require frequent fertilization. However, a light application of balanced fertilizer in early spring can promote healthy growth. These plants are typically resistant to pests and diseases. With their enchanting blooms heralding the arrival of spring, narcissus bring a touch of joy and elegance to any garden.
    </string>

    <!--Dandelion-->
    <string name = "Dandelion">
      \t<b>Plant Name:</b> Dandelion\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Taraxacum\n\t<b>Description:</b> Taraxacum is the scientific name for the common dandelion, a widespread perennial flowering plant found in various habitats worldwide. Dandelions are known for their distinctive yellow flowers that transform into fluffy white seed heads. They are highly adaptable and can thrive in diverse environments, including lawns, meadows, fields, and even cracks in pavement. Caring for dandelions is relatively simple as they are hardy and resilient. They prefer full sunlight but can tolerate partial shade. Dandelions are adaptable to different soil types but prefer well-drained soil. Regular watering to keep the soil moist is necessary, but overwatering should be avoided. Deadheading the flowers before they turn into seed heads helps prevent their spread. Regular mowing can control their growth and maintain a neat appearance. While some consider dandelions as weeds, their yellow blooms and edible leaves make them appreciated by others in the realm of wildflowers and herbal gardens.
    </string>

    <!--Iris-->
    <string name = "Iris">
        \t<b>Plant Name:</b> Iris\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Iris\n\t<b>Description:</b> Irises are stunning perennial flowering plants known for their elegant blooms and distinctive sword-shaped leaves. They are found in a variety of habitats worldwide, including meadows, wetlands, and garden borders. Irises come in a wide range of colors, including shades of purple, blue, yellow, white, and even bi-colors. To care for irises, it is important to provide them with a location that receives full sun or partial shade, depending on the species. They prefer well-drained soil that is not overly wet. Regular watering is necessary, particularly during dry spells or when they are newly planted. However, they should not be overwatered, as excessive moisture can lead to root rot. Deadheading spent flowers promotes continuous blooming, and cutting back the foliage after it turns yellow or brown helps maintain the plant\'s appearance. Dividing overcrowded clumps every few years rejuvenates the irises and encourages healthy growth. These low-maintenance plants are generally resistant to pests and diseases. With their vibrant and graceful flowers, irises add a touch of elegance to any garden.
    </string>

    <!--Magnolia-->
    <string name="Magnolia">
        \t<b>Plant Name: </b> Magnolia\n\t<b>Scientific Name: </b> Magnolia\n\t<b>Description:</b> Magnolias are beautiful flowering trees or shrubs known for their large, showy blooms and captivating fragrance. They are native to various regions, including Asia, the Americas, and parts of Africa. Magnolias are commonly found in habitats such as woodlands, gardens, and parklands. To care for magnolias, it is important to provide them with a location that receives full sun or partial shade, depending on the species. They prefer well-drained soil that is rich in organic matter. Regular watering, particularly during dry spells or when they are newly planted, is essential to establish strong root systems. Applying a layer of mulch around the base of the tree helps retain moisture and suppresses weed growth. Pruning magnolias should be done carefully, preferably in late winter or early spring, to shape the tree and remove any dead or diseased branches. Fertilizing with a balanced slow-release fertilizer in early spring promotes healthy growth and vibrant blooms. Monitoring for pests and diseases, such as scale insects or leaf spot, is important, and appropriate treatments should be applied if necessary. With their majestic presence and stunning flowers, magnolias are a true delight in any landscape.
    </string>

    <!--Rose-->
    <string name = "Rose">
      \t<b>Plant Name:</b> Rose\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Rosa\n\t<b>Description:</b> Roses, or Rosa, are iconic flowering plants renowned for their exquisite beauty and intoxicating fragrance. They are native to various regions around the world and are widely cultivated in gardens and landscapes. Roses can thrive in different habitats, including gardens, borders, and containers. To care for roses, it is crucial to provide them with a location that receives at least six hours of direct sunlight per day. They prefer well-drained soil that is rich in organic matter. Regular watering is essential, particularly during dry periods, but it is important to avoid overwatering as roses are susceptible to fungal diseases. Mulching around the base of the plants helps retain moisture, regulate soil temperature, and suppress weed growth. Pruning roses in late winter or early spring promotes healthy growth, improves airflow, and encourages abundant blooms. Fertilizing with a balanced rose fertilizer in early spring and again in midsummer provides the necessary nutrients for vigorous growth and prolific flowering. Regularly inspecting roses for pests, such as aphids or blackspot, and promptly treating them helps maintain the plants\' health and beauty. With their stunning blossoms and timeless appeal, roses are a classic addition to any garden.
    </string>

    <!--Sunflower-->
    <string name = "Sunflower">
      \t<b>Plant Name:</b> Sunflower\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Helianthus\n\t<b>Description:</b> Helianthus, commonly known as sunflowers, are vibrant and iconic flowering plants native to North and Central America. They are characterized by their large, showy yellow or orange blooms with dark centers, which follow the movement of the sun throughout the day. Sunflowers thrive in habitats that receive full sun and have well-drained soil. They are often found in fields, meadows, and garden borders. To care for sunflowers, provide them with a location that receives at least six to eight hours of direct sunlight per day. They prefer fertile soil, but they are adaptable and can grow in various soil types. Regular watering, particularly during dry spells or when they are newly planted, is important for establishing strong root systems. Stake taller varieties to support their heavy flower heads. Deadheading spent flowers and removing any damaged or diseased foliage helps maintain the plant\'s appearance. Sunflowers are relatively low-maintenance and do not require frequent fertilization. With their striking beauty and ability to brighten any landscape, sunflowers are a delightful addition to gardens and bring joy to onlookers.
    </string>

    <!--Tulip-->
    <string name = "Tulip">
      \t<b>Plant Name:</b> Tulip\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Tulipa\n\t<b>Description:</b> Tulipa, commonly known as tulips, are enchanting flowering plants native to regions in Europe, Asia, and North Africa. They are known for their vibrant and diverse blooms, ranging from single-colored to multicolored varieties in shades of red, yellow, pink, purple, and white. Tulips are versatile and can be grown in a variety of habitats, including gardens, borders, and containers. To care for tulips, it is important to provide them with a location that receives full sun to partial shade. They prefer well-drained soil that is not overly wet. Plant the bulbs in the fall, at a depth that is roughly three times the bulb\'s height. Regular watering is necessary after planting and during dry periods, but they should not be overwatered to avoid bulb rot. Deadheading spent flowers promotes energy conservation and prevents seed production. Once the foliage turns yellow, it can be trimmed back to allow the bulbs to enter their dormant stage. Fertilize tulips with a balanced bulb fertilizer in early spring to support healthy growth and future blooms. With their captivating beauty and vibrant colors, tulips add a touch of elegance and charm to any garden or floral display.
    </string>

    <!--Water lily-->
    <string name="WaterLily">
        \t<b>Plant Name: </b> Tickseed\n\t<b>Scientific Name:</b> Nymphaea\n\t<b>Description:</b> Nymphaea, commonly known as water lilies, are stunning aquatic plants that thrive in still or slow-moving bodies of water. They are native to various regions around the world and are known for their exquisite floating leaves and vibrant flowers. Water lilies can be found in habitats such as ponds, lakes, and marshes. To care for water lilies, it is essential to provide them with a location that offers full sun exposure. They require a water depth of at least 1 to 2 feet (30 to 60 cm) to ensure their roots are submerged. The water should be calm and not subject to strong currents. Plant the water lily rhizome in a container filled with loamy soil or specialized aquatic planting mix, and gently submerge it in the water. Regular watering is unnecessary as the plant is already submerged. However, it is important to monitor the water level to ensure it does not drop too low. Water lilies are heavy feeders, and fertilizing with a slow-release aquatic fertilizer during the growing season can support healthy growth and abundant flowering. Pruning dead or yellowing leaves and spent flowers helps maintain the plant\'s appearance and prevents the accumulation of debris in the water. With their serene beauty and graceful presence, water lilies bring tranquility and elegance to any aquatic environment.
    </string>
    <string name="plant_identifier">Plant Identifier</string>
    <string name="dictionary">Dictionary</string>
    <string name="picture">Picture</string>
    <string name="you_found_a">You found a:</string>
</resources>

